

Personal Summary

I'm Zakaria Laabsi, specialized in machine learning with a keen interest in quantum computing. Backed by a strong foundation in applied mathematics, I've delved into the nexus of ML and quantum tech. Recently, I highlighted "Data Poisoning" at the S3C cybersecurity conference. My goal: synergizing machine learning with quantum computing's transformative potential.

Contact information

- Address: 2211 Avenue du Père Soulas 34090 Montpellier
- Email: zakaria.laabsi@gmail.com
- Github : zlaabsi
- Porfolio: zlaabsi.github.io
- Mobile: +33 7 82 34 37 85

Languages

- French: Native
- English: Intermediate (B2)
- Spanish: Basic (B1)

Soft Skills

- Autonomy
- Precision & Determination
- Emotional Intelligence
- Creativity

Interests

- Volunteering: Data For Good
- · Sports: Hiking, Climbing
- Hackathons, Self-learning

Zakaria Laabsi

QUANTUM/ML ENGINEER

NATIONALITY: French · DOB: 05/03/1999 · Driving Licence: Category B

Skills

- Quantum Computing: Qiskit, OpenQASM, PennyLane framework.
- Programming: Python, R, C++, CUDA / Numba / PyCUDA
- Machine/Deep Learning: TensorFlow, Pytorch
- Automation : Git, Jenkins, Ansible

Work experience

Data Engineer - Supply Chain, Logistics, Sales & AI

Acelys, Nov 2022 - Now, Full-Time

- · Optimized workflows through specialized data integration and ETL execution.
- Boosted database efficiency via automation and parallel/concurrent programming.
- Enhanced project output with creative Python 'API requests' package development.
- Demonstrated AI vulnerabilities at a cybersecurity convention using a poisoned CNN model.

BI & Data Engineer Intern

Crédit Agricole Technologies & Services, Mar - Aug 2022

- Developed and deployed ETL/DevOps pipelines on ELK suite for process optimization.
- Executed POCs, framed and prioritized business needs for quality maintenance.
- Consolidated data for analytical purposes and automated weekly reporting.
- Created real-time and analytical dashboards on Kibana to enhance process visibility.

Data Scientist Volunteer

Data for Good, 2021 - 2022

- Contributed to healthcare and environmental ML/DL open-source projects.
- Involved in social inclusion and educational open-source initiatives.

Projects

- Quantum Descent Gradient with Qiskit (/quantum_ml)
- Quantum Computing Cybersecurity: QSVM for Malware Classification
- IBM Quantum Explorers program
- ElevenLabs Al Hackathon : Al English Tutor (Generative Al powered app)

Education

2020 - 2022

University & IAE Montpellier

Double Master's Degree in Data Science & Statistics / Risk Management

 ${\it Master thesis: Simulation of Time-Dependent Covariables via a Weibull Distribution}$

2019 - 2020

National University Institute Jean-Francois Champollion

Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics

Bachelor thesis: Impartial Combinatorial Game Theory